Guide to the The Ewing Family Papers
University of Houston Libraries
The Ewing Family Papers
1877-2011
1911-1926
02/2008-020
Ewing, Mary Ellen Williams, 1862-1919; Ewing, Gladys; Ewing, Josie Vesta; Ewing, Presley Kittredge, 1860-
6.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Housed in 6 boxes and organized into 5 series titled: Mary Ellen Ewing, Gladys Ewing, Family Photographs, Presley K. Ewing, and Josie (Vesta) Ewing, this collection documents the feminist activities of Mary Ellen Ewing, Gladys Ewing’s social life, legal and familial concerns of Presley K. Ewing, and the writings and journeys of Josie (Vesta) Ewing.
Biographical Information:
Honorable Presley Kittredge Ewing was born on July 21, 1860 in the Lafourche Parish of Louisiana. He attended preparatory school before earning his Law degree from the University of Mississippi as valedictorian in 1881. In 1882, he settled in Houston, Texas where he became a practicing attorney. Shortly thereafter, on February 10, 1885, Ewing married his seven year long fiancée, Mary Ellen Williams, at “Sunnyside,” her family home in Lafourche Parish.
Both Presley and Mary Ellen made considerable contributions to society as a whole within their own realm of interest. Honorable Ewing was elected and served as President of the Texas Bar Associations in 1899; and in 1905, he was commissioned and served as the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Texas, and he was endorsed by many for U.S. Supreme Court, but was never appointed. Over the years, he became known as a pioneer of the law profession as he developed many great judicial principals of the South. In addition to his professional success, Ewing was also seen as a social leader. For many years he was the President of the ZZ Club, which is the oldest social organization in Texas, and he was a Master Mason, a Knight Templar, a Shriner, an Elk and a Beta-Bheta-Phi.
Mary Ellen, born August 7, 1862 in the St. Mary’s Parish of Louisiana, possessed and accumulated a myriad of distinguishable attributes and accomplishments as well. Her life was characterized by public and philanthropic service, which deservedly placed her in “The Texas Women’s Hall of Fame.” Notably, she was the Chairman of the Legislative Committee of the Harris County Equal Suffrage Association and Honorary President of the Child Welfare League. In addition, she was the first Vice President of State Congress of Mothers and the State Humane Society. She was also known for her advocacy endeavors and feminist activism as she fought for public school reform and advocated for women to be on the school board. Last, but not least, inventor was another role she succeeded in as she was granted three Letters Patent of the United States for developments in street sanitation.
The union of Honorable Presley and Mary Ellen Ewing produced two daughters: Josie Vesta, born February 11, 1886 and Gladys, born April 17, 1893. Both daughters attended private school, graduated from Houston High School at the ages of 16 and earned a post graduate diploma with high honors from the Finch School in New York City. Josie Vesta married Joseph Carroll Vinson at Christ Church (Episcopal), Both daughters were members of the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution as well.
References:
Ewing, Presley Kittredge and Mary Ellen (Williams) Ewing. The Ewing Genealogy with Cognate Branches: A Survey of the Ewings and Their Kin in America. Presley K. Ewing, 1919.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Articles; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Correspondence; Diaries; Photographs; Postcards
Personal Name:
Ewing family; Ewing, Gladys; Ewing, Josie Vesta; Ewing, Mary Ellen Williams, 1862-1919; Ewing, Presley Kittredge, 1860-
Topical Term:
School boards -- Texas -- Houston; Socialites -- Texas -- Houston; Suffragists -- Texas -- Houston; Women -- Political activity -- Texas -- Houston; Women -- Suffrage -- Texas -- Houston
Accruals:
Additional materials were acquired in 2012 as part of donations by Vesta Eidman and Sally Combes Leahey.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Related Materials:
Mary Ellen Ewing vs the Houston School Board digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/p15195coll30)
1911 Houston Society with Gladys Ewing digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/p15195coll23)
Scope and Contents
Housed in 6 boxes and organized into 5 series titled: Mary Ellen Ewing, Gladys Ewing, Family Photographs, Presley K. Ewing, and Josie (Vesta) Ewing, this collection documents the feminist activities of Mary Ellen Ewing, Gladys Ewing’s social life, legal and familial concerns of Presley K. Ewing, and the writings and journeys of Josie (Vesta) Ewing.
Detailed List of Contents
- Mary Ellen Williams Ewing
  Scope and Contents
  This series documents Mary Ellen's distinguishable attributes and accomplishments such as her public and philanthropic service; her placement in “The Texas Women’s Hall of Fame”; her positions as Chairman of the Legislative Committee of Harris County Suffrage Association, Honorary President of the Child Welfare League, and the first Vice President of State Congress of Mothers and the State Humane Society; her advocacy endeavors and feminist activism; and her role as an inventor of street sanitation enhancements.
  - Correspondence
    - Presley K. Ewing and Supreme Court of the United States
      - From W. M. Hobby, November 27, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - From Rep. Benjamin G. Humphries, March 6, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - From Rep. Ezekiel S. Chandler, March 6, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - From Charles McChord, March 22, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - From Sen. W.E. Chilton, March 24, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - From H. Garland Dupré, March 27, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - From Sen. John H. Bankhead, June 20, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - From Rep. Kenneth D. McKellar, June 22, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - From Sen. Joseph E. Ransdell, June 24, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - From Sen. John Sharp Williams, July 14, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Various
      - From Julia Ideson re: Reading List, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - From Fayette Ewing, October 31, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - From F.C. Weinert re: Appointment to the Board of the State Bureau of Child and Animal Protection, July 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - From Jeanne B. Sterns re: Deserting Husbands, July 31, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - From Olive Hull Butler re: General, August 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - From C.B. Gillespie, August 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - From Rep. Martin Dies, March 22, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - From Sen. James Hamilton Lewis re: Support, July 1, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Letter from Mary Ellen Williams, June 15, 1877 (Ovs box 4, Item 5)
      - Letters of Mary Ellen (Mamie) Williams Ewing, 1877-1879, 1888, 1897 (Ovs box 4, Item 6)
  - Social Issues
    - Newsies
      - “Help the Newsies", undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - “Blue Legs of the Newsies”, October 30, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - “Newsies Have Picture Taken”, November 13, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - School Board
      - “ President’s Address”, May 28, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - “Women on the School Board”, April 6, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - “Supt. Doesn’t Want Women on Board”, April 12, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - “Women Should Be on School-bd”, May 6, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - “Letter to school Board in Support of Women”, May 7, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - “Reply From Mrs. Ewing”, May 10, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - “Why Women are Needed”, May 11, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - “Women Are Going to Be On School Board”, May 12, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - “School Board to be Delayed”, May 12, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - “Women Lose in Appeal for School Posts”, May 13, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - “We Shall Yet Win”, May 13, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - “School-BD Remains Purely stag Affair”, May 13, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - “Mayor Criticized by Mrs. P.K. Ewing”, May 14, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - “Will Carry the Fight For Women”, June 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - “Fight Starts for Women On School Board”, June 13, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Trustees Articles, June 21, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - “Regular Meeting of Houston Labor Council”, July 19, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - “Houston Labor Council Endorses Mrs. Ewing”, July 26, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - “Enough Signers Already to Submit Amendment”, August 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - “Voters Will Pass on Women As Trustees”, August 11, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - “Initiative Invoked by Women”, August 12, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - “283 Women teachers Enough Female Influence Says Cage”, September 14, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - “Mrs. Ewing Gives Her Views on City Charter Amendment”, September 21, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - “Women School Advisers Are Ready to Begin Their Work”, September 24, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - “The People, The Schools, and Politics”, September 27, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - “Mrs. Presley K. Ewing Replies to the Mayor and City Attorney”, September 27, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - “Ladies Ask Fair Sex on School-BD”, April 39, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - “Voters Attention! Eleventh Amendment”, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - “Women on School Board”, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - “Women on the Board Would Put Schools in Better Condition", undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - School Conditions
      - Condition of Schools, May 3 & 7, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - “Improvements in City Schools”, May 25, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - “School Needs Pointed Out”, June 29, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - “Politics in the School Room”, July 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Street Sweeper
      - “Dear Sir” Letter, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - “Houston Woman Invents New Street Sweeper that Eliminates Dust”, April 23, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Patent, August 5, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - From Hardway & Cathey, August 9, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - “Houston Society and Club Woman has Invented Vacuum Street Sweeper”, September 28, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - “Dear Sir” Letter, June 15, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      - Street Sweeper Blueprint, undated (Ovs box 4, Item 1)
      - Vacuum Street Sweeper Blueprint, undated (Ovs box 4, Item 2)
    - United Mothers Club
      - “Preparing For Texas Mother’s Convention”, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
      - “Welcome Address to Congress of Mothers”, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
      - “ Gives Her Reasons for Walking Out Of Meeting”, May 16, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      - “Parent-Teachers Body is Divided in Houston”, May 16, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      - “Parent-Teacher Club Divides Into Factions”, May 16, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      - “Women Bolt and Form New Mothers Club”, May 16, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - “United Mothers’ Club Will Continue Fight”, May 18, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      - Encouraging Letter From Annie James, May 19, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - “United Mothers Club Perfected”, May 22, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 70)
      - “Mother’s Club Will Meet at Auditorium”, June 3, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 71)
      - “Mothers of United Club to War For Reforms”, June 4, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 72)
      - “United Mothers Club Has Closing Meeting”, June 4, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 73)
      - Letter from Dallas Seeking Assistance, June 7, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 74)
      - “United Mothers Club Will Start Season”, October 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      - From Mrs. E.C. Johnson re: Resigning as President, October 18, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Women’s Suffrage
      - “The Modern Woman”, undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
      - To Houston Chamber of Commerce re: Women’s Vote, undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
      - “Women Now Possess Rights in Lone Star Commonwealth”, March 23, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 79)
      - “In Keynote Suffrage Address”, April 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 80)
      - “Women Open Campaign For Right to Vote”, May 30, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 81)
      - “Woman Suffrage Speakers Theme”, May 31, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 82)
      - “Woman Suffrage”, June 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 83)
      - “Suffrage a Necessity”, June 8, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 84)
      - “Women Who Enter Business on Own Worth will Succeed”, June 9, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 85)
      - “Dr. Jacobs and Suffrage”, June 22, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 86)
      - From Mrs. Jas. Nye Ryman, June 26, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 87)
      - “Women Speak in Open Air on Equal Suffrage Problem”, July 1, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Various Materials
    - “Death Overtakes Woman Prominent in City Affairs”, undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - “The Red Letter Merchants of Houston”, undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - “The Return of the Minstrel”, March 11, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - “Fifty Story Tellers Were at Press Club”, October 10, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - “Personal Influence", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Autograph Album, 1878-1879 (Ovs box 4, Item 3)
    - Autograph Album belonging to Mamie Ethell Williams, 1880-1902 (Ovs box 4, Item 4)
- Gladys Ewing
  This series documents Gladys Ewing's social engagements in Houston, Texas in the fall of 1911 during the Annual No-Tsu-Oh Festival and the spring of 1912 during the Mardi Gras season. Additional albums kept by Miss Ewing document her social life and attendance while a student at the Finch School for young ladies in New York City from 1909-1911. Her bridal gift registry from 1917 is included, as well as personal journals and scrapbooks. Finally, photographs of Gladys throughout her life finish off the series.
  - Scrapbooks and Journals
    - The Debutante's Diary; Congratulatory Telegrams, November 2, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Debutante Dance Invitation; Debutante Events Memorabilia, November 3, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - For Miss Ewing; Progressive Dinner for Debutante, November 5-6, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Double Box Party at Majestic; Bridge Party for Alice Baber, November 8, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Dinner for Debutante; The King and Queen's Float, November 12, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Debutantes of this Season; Beginning of Carnival Week, November 13, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Luncheon for Prospective Brides; The King, the Queen, Ladies of Court and the Souvenirs, November 14-15, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Nottoc XIII and his Queen; Magnificent Banquet, undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Scene of Splendor at Carnival Coronation Ball; Scene of Splendor at Carnival Coronation Ball (cont.), undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Artwork; Flower Parade, November 16, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Houston Horse and Auto Show Program; Carnival Ball Invitation, November 17, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - No-Tsu-Oh Carnival Ball; Luncheon for Debutantes, November 18-19, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Marguerite Street's Dance at Thalian Club; The Majestic/ Mrs. Holt's Luncheon, November 20-21, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - The Debutantes Cotillion; The Debutantes Cotillion (cont.), November 23, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Gift Remnants- James Rillasterron; Mrs. Carey Sham's Luncheon in Gladys' Honor, November 24, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - The Majestic Theatre; "The Gamblers"/ Dinner-Dance at the Country Club, November 25, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Gift Registry; Gift Registry (cont.), November 25, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Gift Registry (cont.); Gift Registry (cont.), November 25, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Miss Gladys Ewing (photograph)/ Dinner-Dance; Complimentary Luncheon at Country Club, November 26-27, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - "Get Rich Quick Wallingford"/ Thanksgiving Day/ Thalian Ball; "Rip Van Winkle", November 29, December 2, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - The Majestic /King's Box Party for the "Chocolate Soldier"; Carnival Dinner Invitation, December 4-5, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - The Majestic/ "Mutt and Jeff"/ Miss Agnese Carter's Dance; Dance at the Bender, December 6 & 9, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - Bender Dance Invitation and Dance Program; Complimentary Rose Dance, December 15-16, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - With Miss Ewing/ Z. Z. Club Ball; Z. Z. Club Ball Dance Program/ Eileen Lovejoy's Dance, December 17 & 19, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - The "Cozy" and "Dixie"/ The Majestic/ Christmas Day; Christmas Gift Tags, December 20, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Christmas Gift Tags and Cards; Christmas Gift Tags and Cards (cont.), December 20, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Christmas Gift Tags and Cards (cont.); "Excuse Me"/ "The Girl of the Golden West"/ Bridge Party/ Miss Perry's Dinner, December 26, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - New Year's Dinner/ Thalian Ball/ Bridge Party; New Year's Dance, December 31, 1911 & January 3-5, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - "Rebecca of Sunnybrook Farm"; Mrs. W. G. Smiley's Luncheon/ A New Year Revelation by Gladys Ewing, January 10, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Travel to New Orleans to Visit Lois Janvier; New Orleans' Mardi Gras Ball, February 11 & 13, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Sarah Pipes Luncheon/ Momus Parade and Momus Ball; Knights of Momus Dance Program/ Carnival German, February 14 & 16, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - American Beauties; Date with Mr. Ashton Collins- "The Bachelor's Baby", February 17, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - French Opera House- "Krewe of Proteus"; Mardi Gras Day, February 20, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - Mardi Gras Pin with Ribbon; The Royal Party at the Athenaeum, February 20, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - The Royal Party at the Athenaeum (cont.); Honors for Houston Girl/ Houston Girl in New Orleans, February 20, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - Mystick Krewe of Comus; Blank, February 20, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - Carnival Queen and King: Miss Lois Janvier and Mr. George W. Clay; The Queen in her Royal Robes, undated (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - Rex and Merry Krewe Excell Former Efforts; Rex and Merry Krewe Excell Former Efforts (cont.), undated (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - Rex Parade on Canal Street- Rex and his Radiant Queen Receive People's Homage; Lunch at the Cosmopolitan/ "The Man from Home", February 23, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Automobiling to West End/ Shopping with Lois; House Party in Louisiana, February 25, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 133)
    - Boat Trip to Lake in "Glenwater"; Phyllis Bush Visit/ The Majestic, March 2 & April 13, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 134)
    - "Graustauls" /Dinner-Dance at the Galvez/ Telegram; Dinner-Dance at the Galvez Programme, April 16-17, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 135)
    - Ella Boyles Dance Program; San Antonio Visit/ Luncheon for Houston Girl, April 18 & June 25, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 136)
    - Clara May Brooks Garden Party/ For Houston Girl; Natatorium Party and Luncheon in Gladys' Honor, undated (Box 1, Folder 137)
    - Cand Party and Shower/ Automobile Party; Cand Party given by Annette Smidt/ Dinner-Dance at Country Club in Gladys' Honor, undated (Box 1, Folder 138)
    - Bollons - Nix Wedding; Plaza/ Automobile Party, undated (Box 1, Folder 139)
    - Telegram; Blank, undated (Box 1, Folder 140)
    - A Women's Love Dream/ Lonesome; Blank (back of scrapbook), undated (Box 1, Folder 141)
    - New York Social Album, 1909-1910 (Ovs box 4, Item 7)
    - New York Theatre Album, 1909-1910 (Ovs box 4, Item 8)
    - New York Theatre Album, 1909-1910 (Ovs box 4, Item 9)
    - Bridal Gift Registry, 1917 (Ovs box 4, Item 10)
    - “Lest We Forget” Personal Diary of Gladys Ewing, 1913 (Ovs box 5, Item 1)
    - Trip to Houston Scrapbook, Mrs. A.C. Combes, Jr., January 12, 1926 (Ovs box 5, Item 2)
    - Journal of Gladys Ewing, 1904 (Ovs box 5, Item 3)
    - Book of Handwritten Poems Presented to Gladys (Ewing) Combes by the Salon of Seven Arts, May 29, 1936 (Ovs box 5, Item 4)
  - Articles and Letters
    - Various Ewing Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 142)
    - “Old Friends Share a Cup of Tea”, undated (Box 1, Folder 143)
    - “No-Tsu-Oh Royalty Roll Along”, May 9, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 144)
    - “Gladys Ewing Combes: No Legendary Character-She”, January 6, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 145)
    - “Gala Homecoming for Debs of 1911”, January 17, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 146)
    - Speech at Delphian Society Luncheon, undated (Box 1, Folder 147)
    - Letter from Mary Ellen Ewing, October 14, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 148)
    - To Vesta Eidman (Granddaughter) re: Stroke, undated (Box 1, Folder 149)
  - Photographs
    - Display Placards (2), undated (Ovs box 5, Item 5)
    - Graduating Class-Houston High School, June 1909 (Ovs box 5, Item 6)
    - Mrs. Johnson’s Room, 1904 (Ovs box 5, Item 7)
    - Gladys Ewing Combes, undated (Ovs box 5, Item 8)
    - Gladys Ewing age 12, c. 1905 (Ovs box 5, Item 9)
    - Gladys Ewing (Portrait), undated (Ovs box 5, Item 10)
    - Gladys Ewing age 16, c. 1909 (Ovs box 5, Item 11)
    - Gladys Ewing (Portrait), undated (Ovs box 5, Item 12)
    - Gladys Ewing (Full Length), undated (Ovs box 5, Item 13)
    - Gladys Ewing, 1915 (Ovs box 5, Item 14)
- Family Photographs
  This series consists of photographs of the Ewing family as well as several photographs of the family home located in Houston, Texas. Also included are photographs of the Kittredge and Williams family members. A photo CD of scans of some of the photographs also resides in this series.
  - Ewing Family, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 150)
  - Ewing Family Residence, undated (Box 1, Folder 151)
  - Mary Ellen Williams Ewing, undated (Box 1, Folder 152)
  - Newsboys, undated (Box 1, Folder 153)
  - Presley Kittredge Ewing, undated (Box 1, Folder 154)
  - “Sunnyside” Plantation Home of Clark C. and Endora Williams, undated (Box 1, Folder 155)
  - Various Ewing Family Members, undated (Box 1, Folder 156)
  - Various Kittredge Family Members, undated (Box 1, Folder 157)
  - Various Williams Family Members, undated (Box 1, Folder 158)
  - Vesta Eidman Photo CD and Photocopies, undated (Box 1, Folder 159)
  - Vesta and Kittredge Vinson, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 160)
  - Photograph of Ewing House, 1103 Clay Ave, Houston, TX, c. 1900 (Ovs box 5, Item 15)
  - Photograph of 25th Anniversary Gifts in Dining Room, Judge & Mrs. Presley Kittredge Ewing, 1910 (Ovs box 5, Item 16)
  - Photograph of 25th Anniversary Flowers to Judge & Mrs. Presley Kittredge Ewing in the Foyer, 1910 (Ovs box 5, Item 17)
  - Williams Family Vault, April (Ovs box 5, Item 18)
  - Vesta Ewing w/Tambourine, undated (Ovs box 5, Item 19)
  - J. Kittredge Vinson 18-20 yrs. old, undated (Ovs box 5, Item 20)
  - Josie Vesta Ewing Graduation Houston High School, 1902 (Ovs box 5, Item 21)
  - Hall Presley K. Ewing Residence, undated (Ovs box 5, Item 22)
  - Dining Room, undated (Ovs box 5, Item 23)
  - Presley K. Ewing Residence, undated (Ovs box 5, Item 24)
- Presley K. Ewing
  This series consists of correspondence and other documents relating to all aspects of Presley K. Ewing’s life including letters recommending his appointment to the Supreme Court of the United States as well as correspondence regarding legal cases. The bulk of the series contains letters to and from family members, but of particular interest is a series of correspondence with William Jennings Bryan.
  - Correspondence
    - Business
      - Albert Weiblen Marble & Granite Co.
        - From Leila Werlein re: Inscriptions on the C.C. Williams Tomb, February 27, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 161)
        - To Albert Weiblen Marble & Granite Co. re: Inscription, February 28, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 162)
        - From Albert Weiblen re: Inscription, March 2, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 163)
      - J.H. Whitney
        - Telegram from J. H. Whitney re: Greetings, June 16, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 164)
        - From J. H. Whitney re: Cases, June 23, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 165)